这次这个项目开始的契机
是去年 Anime Expo 时  我们经 Crunchyroll 介绍认识了 Porter 先生
A-1 Pictures 社长
落越友则
那是我们第一次见面
This is my third or fourth trip to meet with A-1 Pictures,
这是我第三或是第四次访问 A-1 Pictures
who is the studio that's developing this short film.
这个短片的制作公司
I had no idea when I walked into that room for the first time,
当时我第一次走进那个房间的时候  我根本没有想到
that I was gonna come back to Japan like seven or eight times that year,
那之后一年中我会返回日本七八次
to meet with A-1 Pictures and continue to work on the video.
与 A-1 Pictures 一起进行短片的制作
And I had no idea that...
我也没有想到
...it was gonna be one of the most artistically fulfilling thing I've ever got to do in my life.
那会是我有生以来做过的最有艺术成就感的事之一
老实说　我们当时也怀疑过我们能否成功完成这一项目
但是当 Porter 先生第一次来日本时
我们发现 Porter 先生是位真诚友善的人
企划开发本部 部长
三宅将典
而且感受到了他对日本动画发自内心的喜爱
就觉得无论如何得为他完成这项工作
于是我们开始了这一项目
To be able to write the story and to see it come to life in front of me,
能够创作这个故事并亲眼见证短片的诞生过程
It's...I cannot describe the feeling...
这种感觉我无法用语言来描述…
Initial conversations that we had when we first met with them,
我觉得我们初次见面时的对话
I think it was a perfect way for us to get this mutual understanding of...
是达到相互理解的最好方式
something that's really serious,
比如我们确实是想认真完成这件事
and we want this thing to have a lot of integrity, and we want it to be really beautiful.
还有我们希望这部短片有很高的完成度  而且要非常美好
The look that I wanted to go for was very much like A-1 style.
我所追求的效果也非常符合 A-1 的风格
与我们这些一直从事动画制作的人相比  Porter 先生能体会到 有所不同的东西
这对于我们来说是一种很强的刺激
我们期待着联手创作出有新意且与众不同的作品
The video for Shelter is the most concrete distillation of being completely immersed into fantasy,
《避难所》这部短片是从完全沉浸于幻想世界的体验中提炼的精华
and the wierd ways that's connecting with reality nowdays with like virtual reality,
同时却又通过虚拟现实这种奇异的技术将当下的现实联系起来
and the fact that most of our experience of life now is in some way connected to technology.
以及事实上我们现代生活中的大多数体验都以某种方式和技术有所关联
The world of Shelter, this virtual reality universe that she's stuck in,
她所陷入的“避难所”这个虚拟现实世界
where she has this super power to create environments,
在这里她拥有造物主一般的力量
and go around and play in them and explore them every day,
并每天在里面玩耍和探索
just think that it's a really really beautiful notion,
我觉得这个想法非常之美
and something that's really dear and relevant to my own sensibility as an artist.
同时这对于我身为艺术家的感知力来说也是非常珍贵且息息相关的
这部 MV 正如前面所说
是把以前从未尝试过的形式和出发点以及实现方法糅合了起来
The nature of working with animation is that you need to be involved in every step of the process.
动画制作的工作性质决定了你必须参与到每一个步骤中去
From character designs, and environment designs, and writing the story,
从角色设计到场景设计  编写故事情节
and then actually storyboarding it, and then doing animatics.
再到分镜设计  以及制作动态分镜
You need to be very very close to the process,
你必须紧密地参与到整个过程中
because you can't ask for changes once you have something finished to look at.
因为一些东西一旦确定就无法再修改了
要说这个项目中最有趣的地方
在于从来没有过的合作方和艺术家
以及制作方式和团队构成
能在这样的环境下完成工作是非常有趣的
I wanted to pick up a popular name. I liked Rin a lot for this character, I liked that name.
我想给主角起一个有人气的名字  我很喜欢“凛”这个名字
Just so happenes that the CEO of A-1 Pictures' daughter is named Rin.
结果碰巧 A-1 Pictures 的 CEO 的女儿就叫凛
which meant they took a real liking to the charater into the project.
看来他们是真心喜爱这个角色
And when I found that out,
我发现这件事情后  说
I was like "Oh wow! OK, that's too weird, we can change the charater name."
哎呀  这可不好  要不我们改个名字吧
They were like "No, don't...keep it, keep it as Rin."
他们却说  别别  就这样  就要“凛”
which I was really happy with.
我对此也非常满意
You will be amazed by just how even their drafts and sketches, how incredible those looked.
即便只是草稿和原画  你都会惊讶于它们的质量
There were so many conversations about what Rin's room would look like.
关于凛的房间应该是什么样子  我们做了大量的讨论
Viewers won't see 90% of those sketches,
那些原画的百分之九十  观众们都不会看到
and though barely see her room in the animation.
也很难看到短片中她那只出现了一幕的房间
It's a really really extensive process.
这是一个非常浩大的制作工程
The only surprise for me having worked on other animation projects before...
和以前参与其他动画制作相比  唯一让我震惊的地方就是
...was just the incredible level of quality to which A-1 did it.
A-1 那不可思议的制作质量
我觉得这个项目中最有趣之处就在于 Porter 先生本人
比如他为何创作出了那样的音乐  为何受人喜爱
以及他对创作的热情和想象力
To actually collaborate on creating anime is just...it's unbelievable.
真正参与合作制作动画  这件事太不可思议了
And...I had several moments when I was in their studios,
有好几次在他们的工作室里我就在想
where I was just like..."this is happening right now, I'm getting to do this.
这一切正在发生  我就正在做这件事
I'm like getting to work with these people, and create this character,
我真的就在和这些人一起创造出这个角色
this girl in this universe in this story.
这个故事里生活在这个世界中的女孩
I had a moment where I was like "You know what, even if the world can never see this video,
有一瞬间我就在想  你知道么  就算全世界谁也看不到这个短片
the process alone would have made it all worth it."
仅是这个制作过程就很值得了
For me the fact that people gonna get to see this,
对我来说  人们会看到这个短片
beyond just me saying it, it's even more incredible.
而不只是我说说而已  就更加不可思议了